There are cabinet members
who question whether you're fit
to continue as chief executive of this country.
We are invoking the 25th Amendment.
I intend to show your erratic and irrational
behaviour since the start of this crisis.
You see the results. The vote is against you.
Please remove yourself from
the decision-making process.
I swear that I will faithfully execute the
office of the President of the United States,
so help me God.
I got a message that the president
called off the military offensive.
- Is it true?
- Yes.
- You knew about it?
- I did.
Why keep my people processing
intel on a scrapped operation?
There's a strong possibility
the White House will reinstate the attack.
- Dad?
- Sweetheart.
- I've been trying to reach you.
- Are you at the sheriff's station?
They're taking me to the Mathesons' house
to pack up my things. Glad you're OK.
Me too.
- Have you got the audio file?
- No.
Are you saying there's
no audio file on that chip?
If there were, they were destroyed.
Michelle traced the sequence
to a hacker named Alex Hewitt.
- He created the Cyprus audio file?
- Yes.
(Jack) I'm checking up on a man
who engineered the recording.
(Palmer) Are you convinced
that the Cyprus recording is forged?
(Jack) Yes, sir, without a doubt.
Alex?
- Hewitt's not here.
- I'm not surprised.
Check the garage, see if his car's still here.
Even with the delay, we predict
we have not lost the element of surprise.
As you can see here, sir, the primary
targets are still relatively unguarded.
Resistance should be insignificant.
- When were these pictures taken?
- Ten minutes ago, sir.
Then we can proceed
with the attack as planned.
Yes, Mr President.
I need your key codes, sir.
How much longer will Prescott detain me?
Until after the press conference.
In a couple of hours, he's going
to announce the US response to the bomb,
and his ascension to the office.
Your key codes belong
to President Prescott now. It's protocol.
Confirmed.
Know why Chappelle called this meeting?
No, he just told everybody
to save their work and get in here.
This information is confidential.
It'll stay inside until it's been made public,
which should be in the next few hours.
The cabinet invoked the 25th Amendment
and removed David Palmer from office.
- Jim Prescott is now the president.
- Why?
That isn't relevant to our charge.
- Yes, it is, Ryan.
- What's your problem, Almeida?
We know Palmer was removed cos
he didn't wanna go on with the bombings.
That makes what Bauer's
doing more relevant.
Bauer has cried wolf twice already.
He's come up with nothing.
I have an order from District
that disallows any further resources
from being expended on him.
Why is everybody so afraid to look at all
the sides of this? What if Bauer's right?
What if it was forged and we're about
to bomb three innocent countries?
Tony, let me first say that your office
has done a remarkable job today.
There is no way the people on the Hill
are not going to reward every one of you
for your role in averting disaster.
- What does that have to do with anything?
- Let me finish.
The success of this office today
is due in large part to the technical team.
The same team that has concluded
that the Cyprus audio
is an untreated, unforged original.
There comes a time when you have
to let go. Not every hunch works out.
Bauer's chasing a ghost.
I can't put it any simpler than that.
That's all.
- What are you gonna do?
- I have to talk to one of Prescott's staff.
If Jack comes in with the evidence,
we need somebody in place to take it to.
If Chappelle finds out
you're doing an end run...
I know. I know.
- The car is gone.
- OK.
- (man) What do you wanna do?
- (Sherry) Kingsley took anything important.
- (Sherry) We gotta find Hewitt. Let's go.
- Stop right there!
- Sit down!
- Let go of me!
Don't move. Don't move!
Who are you? Don't look at her,
look at me! Who are you?
- I'm nobody.
- He's my private bodyguard.
- Secret Service?
- Ex.
- Mrs Palmer.
- Jack Bauer.
- Stand up.
- Why?
- Stand up!
- What are you gonna do to me?
Turn around.
I'm not carrying any weapons.
Take a seat.
- Why are you here?
- Trying to help David.
- You're no longer part of his life.
- Don't believe everything you read.
David's asked me to pool my resources to
see if I can find out who's behind the bomb.
- I don't believe you.
- I don't care what you believe.
Do you know who did this?
Who ransacked this place?
- You're here for the same reason I am.
- What reason would that be?
- To find Alex Hewitt.
- Why?
- You must know. You're here.
- Why don't you tell me?
He created a recording
that's about to start a war.
How do you know about that?
I don't like the way
this conversation is going.
- How do you know about Cyprus audio?
- How dare you talk down to me!
I am not a politician.
I will not debate this with you.
Answer me. What do you know
about the Cyprus recording?
Every expert in the government
with priority clearance
has been working on it for six hours.
I've got a lot of sources.
- What do you know about Alex Hewitt?
- That he's a freelance audio technician.
- Who does he work for?
- A man named Peter Kingsley.
Why?
Kingsley represents Caspian Sea
oils interests that want the US
at war with the Middle East. Kingsley hired
Hewitt to fabricate the Cyprus recording.
Mr Bauer, I've walked the corridors
of power my entire life.
You'd be surprised how much information
you can get if you have something to trade.
- What are you doing?
- Take a seat.
Take a seat!
Come out!
Open the door slowly,
I wanna see both your hands! Now! Now!
Please don't hurt me!
- Get on the ground!
- OK. OK.
Don't move. Get on the ground!
Who are you?
- Mrs Palmer?
- Alex.
You said you would help me.
Why does he have a gun?
- Shut up. Go sit with her.
- I didn't do anything wrong.
- Move!
- You said you'd...
Shut up. Don't say anything.
He's a federal agent.
- Shut up.
- I am not talking to you!
- Shut up!
- Don't say anything, Alex.
Alex, don't say anything!
You're gonna talk to me now.
You took voice samples from three leaders
and intercut them with Ali's for the audio?
- I didn't say that.
- And Kingsley paid you.
- No!
- You're a traitor.
- You know what they'll do to you?
- I'm not. I didn't know, I swear.
I told Mrs Palmer. She'll tell you.
Forget about her. She can't help you.
But if you tell me everything about
the Cyprus audio, I'll do what I can.
- I won't say anything until I see a lawyer.
- I am your lawyer, son.
Those people you worked for thought
you'd die in the bomb. They're after you.
If you wanna stay alive,
start telling me everything.
No, I only wanna talk to Mrs Palmer.
Why her? How's she connected to this?
How do you know her?
I just met her today.
She called, said she could help me.
I know she's the president's ex-wife.
She's got connections high up.
She can't help you now, Alex.
I'm the only one who can help you now.
I wanna to talk to her.
OK. Let me see what I can do.
Give me your keys.
- Why?
- Give me your keys.
- Which one of these locks this door?
- This one.
Just step back.
- What did he say?
- Why are you here?
Please don't tell me it's to help the president.
All right. I came here to protect myself.
Alex was paid by Kingsley
to record certain conversations.
Some of those were with me,
they incriminate me.
You're collaborating with Peter Kingsley?
He assured me that the bomb
would never go off.
What were you thinking?
What the hell were you thinking?
- Who are you calling?
- CTU.
I'm a sworn federal agent.
You just confessed to a federal crime.
- I suggest you hang up that phone.
- I need to speak to Tony Almeida.
I am the only one
who can get Hewitt to cooperate.
And for that, I'll want
full immunity from prosecution.
Now hang up the phone
and I'll tell you everything.
- Jack, it's Tony, what's going on?
- I'm gonna have to get back to you.
Start.
- Start!
- I wanted to bring down David's presidency.
I was so angry with David
for what he did to me.
I worked tirelessly for years to put him
into office. I sacrificed everything.
My career, my family. David betrayed me.
So you wanted revenge.
What did Kingsley want?
Money. A war in the Middle East
would triple the value of his oil.
You're here to ensure
no one connects you to Kingsley.
Yes, like I told you, I came to protect myself.
Look, Mr Bauer, there's only one person
you need to prosecute for this.
And that person is sitting in that room there.
I want full immunity.
Otherwise, it's just your word against mine.
She'll talk with you.
- I know you're scared.
- You said I would be OK.
I know there's been a little wrinkle,
but we can fix that.
What do you think, Aaron? You think
I'm unfit to fulfil my duties as president?
Sir, I'm under orders
not to discuss this with you.
Are you under orders not to listen?
- No, sir.
- Good.
Then I'll do all the talking.
I assume you remember Jack Bauer.
He believes the Cyprus recording,
the single piece of evidence
propelling us into this war,
was fabricated.
I've been removed from office
because I believe in Bauer.
If it wasn't for Jack, Los Angeles
would be a killing field by now.
Still, Prescott and the cabinet
refuse to believe that he might be right.
If Jack finds the evidence after the planes
have dropped their payloads,
then it'll be too late.
We will be at war against
three innocent countries.
I'm sure if Jack Bauer finds evidence,
Vice President Prescott...
I mean, the president, will recall the bombers.
- You're under orders not to speak to me.
- I'm doing my best, sir.
- Your best would be to help me.
- By doing what?
I need to talk to Jack Bauer.
Find out if he's secured the evidence.
If I remember correctly,
you have a son in the Navy.
Yes, sir, I do.
It's a fine thing to defend one's country.
You should be proud.
Let's make sure the cause
he's fighting for is the just one.
Get me a sat phone. I need a secure line.
Put these in the overnight database.
Chappelle's gonna need 'em for his briefing.
Why are you giving this to me?
This is your situation report.
I'm on something else.
What else?
I don't have to explain myself
to you, Carrie. Just do it.
You do need to explain yourself
cos I think you're going behind
Chappelle's back, trying to help Jack Bauer.
Do you really wanna do this, Carrie?
Come after me?
I've been letting you get away with a lot,
but if you want the gloves to come off, fine.
What's going on here?
She's asking me to take on some of
her workload. I just wanna know why.
Why don't you wanna tell her?
It's none of her business, Tony.
Look, just tell her, so we can
get back to work here.
All right.
District's asked me to step in as a liaison
to facilitate the power shift.
I'll be on the phone for the next two hours.
Sounds like a promotion. Congratulations.
- You think she believed me?
- No.
Go over it again.
Look, I need you to find it fast,
even if you need to pull agents who can
help you. This needs to take first priority.
Division's breathing down
my neck for some reason.
- That's something I don't need.
- I'll take care of it.
All right.
- Mr Chappelle.
- Yes, Carrie?
In my opinion, Tony Almeida's
not fit to run CTU.
- Why not?
- He's got Michelle working off book.
- Doing what?
- I can't say for sure.
But I have a feeling the two of them
are still trying to help Bauer.
Thank you.
(Sherry) It'll be fine.
- (phone ringing)
- Here you go, thanks.
- Almeida.
- Tony, it's Jack.
- What's happening?
- President still holding off on the attack?
Things have gotten worse.
It's not public, but Palmer's been pulled.
- What do you mean?
- His cabinet invoked the 25th Amendment
because he wanted to wait
for confirmation of the recording.
Prescott's now president.
I'll bring evidence proving the recording's
been forged. Prescott won't listen to it?
He won't wait for it. Get me that evidence
quickly, and I'll call Prescott with it.
Start by sending a chopper
to the address you gave me.
- I got Hewitt.
- He definitely made the recording?
- Yes, absolutely.
- Will he testify?
We're working on it.
If I go to Chappelle and request
a chopper for you, he'll deny it.
- He's got orders from District.
- Deal with it, Tony.
We got bombers in the air.
Hewitt's our only chance of stopping this.
I'll do my best.
OK, thanks, Tony.
I know, Alex. I understand your concern.
But the fact remains, we both made a mistake.
But we're lucky because they need us.
Any deal I make will include you, and vice
versa. Remember, we're in this together.
Are you sure about this?
Honey, I would never lie to you.
But you have to remember this one thing.
I am the only one looking after
your interest. No one else.
I know how these things work.
Just do as I say, and it'll all turn out well.
What about him?
Don't worry about him. I'll handle
Agent Bauer. He won't be a problem.
He's very low on the food chain.
So, if I do this, you can keep me out ofjail?
Absolutely. You'll be granted
full immunity just like I promised.
OK?
All right, Jack, this is how it's gonna work.
He'll come in and testify.
He can demonstrate the technology
in a matter of minutes.
Good. The chopper's on its way.
You heard Chappelle. He won't let us
have a chopper if he knows it's for Jack.
But Jack's got Hewitt,
who definitely made that recording.
- Chappelle can't ignore that.
- He can do whatever he wants.
Yeah. Mm-hm. OK.
Let me get back to you, Marc.
- What?
- Jack Bauerjust contacted us.
Really? Where is he?
- North Hollywood.
- What's he doing?
He wants to bring in the guy
who forged the Cyprus recording.
Fine, let him.
He's too far away. We need to send a chopper.
We've been through this, Tony.
I'm done with Bauer.
He's chasing a trail that leads nowhere.
We're onto other things.
More important than the US launching
military strikes based on false information?
The thing is, Tony, you've been reassigned.
Reassigned? Where?
I'll let you know in a few days.
For now, you can go home.
Ryan, you can't reassign me now.
This recording is real. We are going to war.
We need to prepare for domestic response.
You have made yourself a liability
I just can't afford.
You've got 15 minutes
to clean out your desk and get out.
What are you doing?
They took the disk that had my comb filter.
I'll need to rebuild that file to demonstrate.
OK, the tarball has to decompress.
It'll take about 20 minutes.
- How's it gonna work?
- I'll make a recording.
Right on the spot, shift it around,
reframe segments.
It'll have the same specs as Cyprus.
It'll blow their minds.
- Good.
- And then I'm free to go, right?
That's what she said.
Yes, you'll be fine, Alex.
How come you're being
so nice all of a sudden?
- What do you mean?
- Before, it was all my fault,
you called me a traitor,
and now everything's "Fine, Alex"?
- You're gonna screw me.
- We won't screw you.
You two made a deal,
you're gonna hang me out.
Alex, calm down. We can't hang you out.
You have the proof.
- Without you, there is no deal.
- Then I want it in writing.
- Why can't I have an attorney?
- No time.
There are bombers in the air to start a war.
- You'll have to trust me.
- Why should I trust you?
Why don't you have federal counsel
meet us wherever we're going?
- Excuse me?
- One phone call.
- That's right. We want federal counsel.
- No. I'm not trading with you, Alex.
You're gonna do your demonstration,
then I help you. That's the deal. That's it.
- I wanna talk to you in private.
- What are you doing?
- I handled everything.
- What are you afraid of?
I'm the one who can make this happen.
I wanna talk to him alone.
OK, all right, whatever you want.
I'll be over here.
- What's going on?
- Is she trying to screw me?
- No. She's trying to help you.
- Why? I mean, she doesn't even know me.
Maybe because she thinks
you got tricked into doing something
you didn't fully understand.
She wants to use her influence
with the president to try and help you.
- Because she thinks I'm innocent?
- Yeah, maybe.
And I think she likes me.
I think she does.
- Do you need any help?
- No, it should only be one suitcase.
- Take your time. I'll be waiting in the car.
- Thanks.
He just reassigned you?
He didn't give any explanation?
Chappelle doesn't want me in the job. He's
got his own people, and I'm not one of them.
- What are you going to do?
- (phone ringing)
Tony, it's Satcom.
- Almeida.
- This is David Palmer.
Mr President, what can I do for you, sir?
I need to speak to Bauer.
Can you reach him?
- Can you hold on, sir?
- For a moment.
(phone rings)
- Yeah?
- Jack, it's Tony.
- I have President Palmer on the line.
- OK, good. Patch him through.
How we doing on the chopper?
- Working on it.
- Work faster.
Here's the President. Mr President,
I have Jack on the line. Jack, go ahead.
Yes, Mr President.
I don't know if you've heard,
but I've been unseated.
Yes, I have. I'm sorry.
Where are you on your investigation?
I can tell you the Cyprus audio
has been forged.
I have the man who engineered it.
I'm bringing him in soon.
We'll patch him through to the
White House, so he can testify.
Meanwhile, CTU is trying to process
everything they can on him.
Mr President, there is something else though.
What?
Your ex-wife, sir. Sherry, she's here with me.
How did that happen?
- Jack?
- Yes, sir.
- You can't talk?
- No, sir.
Don't trust her, Jack. Do you understand?
Yes, Mr President.
- Let me talk to her.
- He wants to talk with you.
- David?
- What are you trying to do?
- I'm just trying to help you.
- How can you help me?
You shouldn't have lied to me.
That's the problem, David.
It's not always about the truth.
And what's that supposed to mean?
The truth is, the Cyprus recording was forged.
You are right and they are wrong.
The truth is, you're trying
to prevent an unnecessary war,
and Jack Bauer and I are
the only ones who can help you.
- Stay out of his way, Sherry.
- All right. All right, David.
Let me talk to Jack.
- Yes, Mr President?
- I need this man to come forward now.
- I understand, sir.
- All right. Thank you.
- Tony, you still there?
- I'm here.
- How much time have we got?
- Six minutes.
- Tony, can you hear me?
- Go ahead.
- We need that chopper now.
- You'll have it.
Thank you.
I'm gonna need your help.
I'm still here at the Matheson house.
- Where is it, sir?
- Where is what?
Please, David, don't make me do this.
Give me the phone.
- Place Pierce under arrest.
- Mike, don't.
- I coerced him into getting it for me.
- You didn't coerce anyone.
Shame on you,
for placing us both in this position.
It should be you putting yourself
on the line. Instead, Aaron did.
- I tried to be a friend to you, sir.
- I don't want a friend!
I need someone to do the right thing.
I'm sorry, Aaron.
There's nothing to be sorry for, Mr President.
Officer, is that you?
Hello?
(phone rings)
- Dessler.
- You ready?
- Yeah.
- All right, let's go.
(dialling)
(phone rings)
- Yeah.
- Rudin needs you. He's in Holding Room 2.
- Tell him to call me.
- The comm's out in that room.
All right, I'm on my way.
Where's Rudin?
I got this.
Go send that chopper to pick up Jack.
- When are your people getting here?
- Soon.
It's notjust out of my own selfish desire
that I'm trying to stay clean on all this.
Really?
It wouldn't be good for David's presidency
if his ex-wife was implicated in this bomb.
So, now you care about his presidency?
In light of what's happened today,
my resentments seem obscenely petty.
I don't know what I was thinking.
There's something I haven't
told you yet about Mr Palmer.
- Mr Palmer?
- Yes, Mr Palmer.
His cabinet invoked the 25th Amendment
less than an hour ago.
- What?
- Prescott's president now.
- Oh, my God.
- (phone ringing)
You got what you wanted. Yeah.
It's Tony. The chopper's about
to leave. ETA's about 20 minutes.
- So, Chappelle's on board with us?
- Not exactly.
- What do you mean?
- It's better if you don't know.
You'll have to get
the Attorney General involved.
- What for?
- Mrs Palmer wants to cut a deal.
- A deal?
- Hewitt's testimony incriminates her.
- I'll make sure it's in place.
- It has to go like clockwork.
- There's no margin for error.
- I know.
What did you mean, "I want to cut a deal"?
I explained to you that Alex won't say
anything without my permission.
All I care about now is that
he convinces Prescott and the Joint Chiefs
that he forged the Cyprus audio.
- After that, you're free to try and cut a deal.
- That is not what we discussed.
- I'm sorry, that's the way it is.
- We'll see about that.
Mrs Palmer, the conversations end here.
You don't talk to him again,
do you understand me?
Don't try me, Mrs Palmer.
Take a seat on the couch.
(panting)
Kim?
You know this is all your fault, don't ya?
Carla would probably still be alive
if it wasn't for you. Probably.
You think I wanted to hurt her? I didn't.
I loved her.
(phone rings)
- CTU. Dessler.
- This is Kim. I need to speak to my father.
- Kim, your Dad's not here right now.
- Please find him. It's an emergency.
All right, hold on.
(phone rings)
- Yeah.
- It's Michelle. Your daughter's on the line.
OK, fine. Put her through.
- OK, Kim, go ahead.
- Dad.
- Sweetheart, what's wrong?
- I'm at the Mathesons' house.
Gary was here. He has a gun.
- He killed the officer that brought me here.
- Where is he now?
He's passed out. I knocked him out.
- OK, get out of the house.
- What if I killed him?
It doesn't matter.
Just get out of the house now.
OK.
Oh, God! No!
- Kim, what's going on?
- He's moving.
- Grab his gun.
- I've got it.
- Shoot him.
- What?
- I can't.
I want you to point the gun at his chest
and pull the trigger.
No, I can't.
Kim, shoot him now!
Kim. You little bitch.
Kim! Kim!
- Kim, can you hear me?
- Dad!
- Did you do it?
- (crying) Yeah.
Again. I want you to shoot him again.
Shoot him again now, Kim.
Shoot him again now!
(screams)
- Dad?
- Is he dead?
- Yeah.
- OK, sweetheart, listen to me.
I'll send someone to pick you up now.
Go downstairs and wait. Can you do that?
- Yeah.
- OK, baby, hurry.
- Where you going?
- I don't trust you any more.
Everyone is looking to hunt you down:
Kingsley, the government.
We can help you. Without us,
you don't stand a chance.
(phone rings)
- Hello?
- Kate, it's Jack Bauer.
- Is everything all right?
- No. I need your help.
My daughter was in a shooting,
I think she's in shock.
Take the police officer
that I left behind with you,
and go and pick her up
and take her over to CTU.
- I'm sorry, Jack, I sent the officer home.
- Son of a bitch.
- I don't know what else to do.
- I could do it. Go pick up Kim.
- Can you?
- Yeah.
Please call the police and tell them
to meet you at 12, Bluetree Drive.
OK, do you know where it is?
- Yeah.
- OK. I'll call CTU now.
- OK, I'll leave right away.
- Please, Kate, hurry.
- Get out of my way.
- No.
Alex, get back to work!
Sherry, stay away from him!
I need to speak to Tony Almeida
and Michelle Dessler.
- (woman) Is it an emergency?
- Yes, it's an emergency.
Alex, you...
Alex!
Help me.
Visiontext Subtitles: Yasmin Rammohan
ENGLISH SDH